Miami, Florida (786) 457-7729 juliangottlieb.com hello@juliangottlieb.com

Skillset

User-interface design, dynamic content integration, mobile first (responsive) web design, full site development process, HTML/CSS/JS, Bootstrap, jQuery, React.js, SASS, OOCSS, GIT, Gulp, Photoshop, Sketch

Summary

With over 15 years of digital design experience, Julian specializes in user interface design, and is adept at both creating a visual language and designing within an established visual language. Though he excels at UI design, he also understands the full design process and capable of carrying a design through to markup and CSS.

Employment

GIS-RS Center | Frontend Designer | 2008 - Present

- Created and implemented user interfaces for multiple mapping applications and web sites.
- Led production on a range of web projects through the entire life-cycle (information gathering, planning, designing, developing, testing).
- Designed the wireframes. prototypes, and responsive interfaces for various cross-device applications.
- Supervised and directed GIS Center Web developers.
- Designed and prototyped the FIU Libraries and GIS Center websites, and integrated both designs into Drupal CMS.

Geoflik, LLC. | Co-founder, CCO | 2013 - 2016

- Led the visual design of Geoflik's app interface and website.
- Created marketing material, including the company's logo, and all business and information cards.
- Integrated the website design into Drupal CMS while emphasizing a mobile first approach.
- Participated in weekly meetings providing user interface and design input.

Freelance Designer | 2008 - 2014

- Generated fresh ideas and original user interfaces, conceptualized and illustrated logos.
- Built dynamic, content-managed Web sites using Drupal and Wordpress CMSs.

Lunar Logic | Web Designer | 2007

- Communicated with clients to create concept designs based on input and feedback from clients.
- Produced XHTML/CSS/JS functional prototypes.
- Worked closely with programmers on a variety of CMSs and frameworks to integrate designs.

CORE Communications | Web Designer | 2006 - 2007

- Accurately translated client wants and needs into concepts for Web site designs and Flash animations.
- Implemented CSS and XHTML to visually best represent concept designs on multiple browsers and platforms.
- Integrated frontend designs with CORE Communication's proprietary CMS (Core Suite).
- Created company advertisements for newspapers, magazines, flyers and brochures.

Astro Data Services | Web Designer | 2004 - 2006

- Converted Astro Online Service Bureau (AOSB) Web application to standards-compliant XHTML.
- Implemented design improvements to the AOSB Web application.
- Spearheaded the redesign of the Astro Help System via a context-sensitive help framework throughout the AOSB site.
- Redesigned the corporate Web site to compliment the company's marketing approach.

Education

Florida International University, Miami, Florida, 1997-2002

Bachelor of Science in Environmental Studies Graduate Certificate in Geographic Information Systems